Guide to the Ira and Edita Morirs Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Manuscripts
  - Subseries III.2: Edita Morris
    - "The Seeds of Hiroshima", book reviews, 1965-1968 (Box 28, Folder 458)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, p.1-150, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 459)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, p.151-282, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 460)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, p.283-375, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 461)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft, final version, p.1-135, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 462)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft, final version, p.136-272, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 463)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft, text in Swedish, p.1-120, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 464)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft, text in Swedish, p.121-255, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 465)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft, text in Swedish, p.256-330, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 466)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft, final copy, text in Swedish, p.1-131, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 467)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft, final copy, text in Swedish, p.132-255, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 468)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, complete draft, final copy, text in Swedish, p.256-330, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 469)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, p.1-130, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 470)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, p.131-273, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 471)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, p.274-355, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 472)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, incomplete draft, photocopy, p.1-140, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 473)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, incomplete draft, photocopy, p.141-231, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 474)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, proof with handwritten corrections, text in Swedish, p.1-100, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 475)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, proof with handwritten corrections, text in Swedish, p.101-188, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 476)
    - "The Seventy Years War", novel, fragments, text in Swedish, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 477)
    - "The Seventy Years War", book reviews, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 478)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft, p.1-135, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 479)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft, p.136-172, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 480)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, photocopy, p.1-115, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 481)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, photocopy, p.116-172, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 482)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft with changes for Dutch edition, p.1-134, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 483)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft with changes for Dutch edition, p.135-172, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 484)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, text in French [#1], p.1-115, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 485)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, text in French [#1], p.116-151, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 486)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, text in French [#2], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 487)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, text in French [#3], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 488)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#1], p.1-120, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 489)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#1], p.123-171, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 490)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#2], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 491)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, final version, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 492)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, fragments with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 493)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 494)
    - "The Solo Dancer", novel, fragments, text in French, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 495)
    - "The Solo Dancer", theatrical adaptation, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 496)
    - "The Solo Dancer", publication contract for French edition, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 497)
    - "The Solo Dancer", book reviews, 1972-1973 (Box 33, Folder 498)
    - "The Sorrow of Ape-in-pants", short story, published version appearing in American Dialog, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 499)
    - "Stars on Your Forehead", novel, complete draft, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 500)
      [See also "Greek Tragedy in Nineteen Acts", box 19, folder 320; "The Toil and the Deed", box 35, folder 529 and box 36, folder 530-533]
    - "Stars on Your Forehead", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections [#1], n.d. (Box 33, Folder 501)
    - "Stars on Your Forehead", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections [#2], n.d. (Box 33, Folder 502)
    - "Stars on Your Forehead", novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 503)
      [See also "Greek Tragedy in Nineteen Acts", box 19, folder 320; "The Toil and the Deed", box 35, folder and box 36, folder 530-533]
    - "The Stone and the Frogs", short story, complete draft (2 versions), n.d. (Box 34, Folder 504)
    - "The Stone and the Frogs", short story, fragments, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 505)
    - "Straightjacket", novel, complete draft, photocopy, p.1-170, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 506)
    - "Straightjacket", novel, complete draft, photocopy, p.171-301, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 507)
    - "Straightjacket", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#1], p.1-140, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 508)
    - "Straightjacket", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#1], p.141-301, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 509)
    - "Straightjacket", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#2], p.2-145, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 510)
    - "Straightjacket", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#2], p.146-311, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 511)
    - "Straightjacket", novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 512)
    - "Straightjacket", novel, notes, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 513)
    - "Straightjacket", publication contract, 18 July 1977 (Box 35, Folder 514)
    - "Straightjacket", book reviews, 1979, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 515)
    - "The Survivors of the Bombs", article, published version appearing in the New Statesman, 2 Aug. 1958 (Box 35, Folder 516)
    - "Survivors of the Bombs", article, published version appearing in Opinion, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 517)
    - "Talk for Munich Publishers", speech, complete draft (2 versions), n.d. (Box 35, Folder 518)
    - "Un Témoignage poignant sur la mort atomique", article, published version, 17 July 1958 (Box 35, Folder 519)
    - "That Day", short story, complete draft, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 520)
      [Letter from Mervyn Jones to Ira V. Morris, 23 July [n.y.], removed to Correspondence series, box 3, folder 44]
    - "Thirteen Years After", essay, complete draft, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 521)
    - "Thirteen Years After", essay, fragment, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 522)
    - "Three Who Loved", reviews, 1945 (Box 35, Folder 523)
    - "Three Who Loved", copyright certificate, 23 Feb. 1945 (Box 35, Folder 524)
    - "Three Who Loved", novel, published excerpt appearing in Neue Auslese, text in German, May 1947 (Box 35, Folder 525)
    - "Three Who Loved", novel, published excerpt appearing in Internationale Echo, text in Dutch, Sept. 1947 (Box 35, Folder 526)
    - "To Be Happy", short story, complete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 527)
    - "To Be Happy", short story, handwritten draft, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 528)
    - "The Toil and the Deed", novel, complete draft, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 529)
      [See also "Greek Tragedy in Nineteen Acts", box 19, folder 320; and "Stars on Your Forehead", box 33, folder 500-502 and box 34, folder 503]
    - "The Toil and the Deed", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 530)
    - "The Toil and the Deed", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, text in French, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 531)
    - "The Toil and the Deed", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 532)
    - "The Toil and the Deed", novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 533)
    - "Turtles", novel, complete draft, photocopy, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 534)
    - "Turtles", novel, incomplete draft, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 535)
    - "University into Army Camp Radio Talk for Sweden", radio program (2 versions), 15 Sept. 1943 (Box 36, Folder 536)
    - "Vi Världens Kvinnor", article, published version, text in Swedish, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 537)
    - "Welcome to Sweden", essay, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 538)
    - "Wir Die Frauen Der Welt", letter, published version, text in German, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 539)
    - "Young Man in an Astrakhan Cap", short story, published version appearing in Harper's Bazaar, Dec. 1942 (Box 36, Folder 540)
    - "Youra", article, complete draft, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 541)
    - "Youra, Youra!", article, published version, text in Swedish, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 542)
    - "Ziua Aceea", article, published version appearing in Cronica, text in Romanian, 11 Aug. 1970 (Box 36, Folder 543)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 544)
  - Subseries III.3: The Flowers of Hiroshima by Edita Morris
    Typescript draft, excerpts, book reviews, adaptations, and other materials about the novel. The Flowers of Hiroshima was successful worldwide and earned Edita Morris the Albert Schweitzer Prize in 1961. Arranged chronologically.
    - Book jacket, text in German, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 545)
    - Dedication, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 546)
    - Excerpts from letters, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 547)
    - Excerpt from novel, published version, text in [Croatian?], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 548)
    - Excerpt from novel, published version appearing in Éditions Julliard, text in French, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 549)
    - Excerpt from novel, published version appearing in Einladung zur Romanlektüre, text in German, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 550)
    - Excerpts of reviews, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 551)
    - Film Project, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 552)
    - Interview, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 553)
    - List of Publishers, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 554)
    - Plot Summary, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 555)
    - Publication History, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 556)
    - Publicity, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 557)
    - Reviews, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 558)
    - Complete draft with handwritten corrections, p.1-95, [1959?] (Box 37, Folder 559)
    - Complete draft with handwritten corrections, p.96-209, [1959?] (Box 37, Folder 560)
    - Book Reviews, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 561)
    - Complete draft, p.1-131, 24 Aug. 1959 (Box 37, Folder 562)
    - Complete draft, p.132-214, 24 Aug. 1959 (Box 38, Folder 563)
    - Radio programs, text in German, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 564)
    - Book Reviews, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 565)
    - Albert Schweitzer Prize, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 566)
    - Book Reviews, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 567)
    - Radio programs, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 568)
    - Script, text in German, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 569)
    - Book Reviews, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 570)
    - Book Reviews, 1963 (Box 38, Folder 571)
    - Book Reviews, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 572)
    - Book Reviews, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 573)
    - Book Reviews, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 574)
    - Operatic adaptation by Jean Kurt Forest performed in Weimar, Germany, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 575)
    - Film Project, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 576)
    - Operatic adaptation by Jean Kurt Forest performed in Berlin, Germany, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 577)
    - Program Note for operatic adaptation (9 versions), 1969 (Box 38, Folder 578)
    - Reviews of operatic adaptation, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 579)
    - Yosegaki celebrating the publication of The Flowers of Hiroshima, text in Japanese, 11 Sept. 1971 (Box 39, Folder 580)
    - Essay by Benjamin Spock, M.D. (2 versions), 6 June 1983 (Box 39, Folder 581)
  - Subseries III.4: Manuscripts by Ira V. and/or Edita Morris
    Manuscripts written by both Ira V. and Edita Morris. Included are manuscripts and miscellaneous fragments attributed to the Morris’s where the individual author can not be determined. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - "Africa Novel", notes (2 versions), n.d. (Box 39, Folder 582)
    - "Biographical Notes", notes, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 583)
    - "Excess of Love", novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 584)
    - "Fumio Nakamura", essay, 1962, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 585)
    - "Gallant Horse", short story, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 586)
    - "Hiroshima Lore", book reviews of A Dark Star by Ronnie Dugger and Life in Death by Robert Jay Lifton, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 587)
    - "L'Homme D'Hiroshima", essay, text in French, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 588)
    - "Morris House Rules for Scrabble", 6 July 1970 (Box 39, Folder 589)
    - "Peace Congress Book", notes, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 590)
    - "Po?egnanie z latem", poem, published version appearing in Nowa Kultura, text in Polish, 1957 (Box 39, Folder 591)
    - ["There had been rain in…."], novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 592)
    - "Thoughts on the Coming PEN Congress in Tokyo", essay, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 593)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 594)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, text in French, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 595)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, text in German, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 596)
- Series IV: Writings by Others
  Poems, essays, short stories, and other manuscripts written by authors other than Ira V. and Edita Morris. Arranged alphabetically by author's last name.
  - Aveline, Claude "The Bird-That-Never-Was", poem, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 597)
  - Chesneaux, Jean "Les Indiens du Minnesota", essay, published version appearing in Lettres Nouvelles, text in French, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 598)
  - Chesneaux, Jean "Lettre de Detroit", essay, text in French, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 599)
  - Collins, L. John "St. Matthew vi.33", sermon, 26 July 1964 (Box 39, Folder 600)
  - Corbelar, Camilla "Geheimstes Aus Verborgensten Tympanen", poems, text in German, [1969] (Box 39, Folder 601)
  - Johnson, Russell "Report from Southeast Asia", report, July 1970 (Box 40, Folder 602)
  - Jungk, Robert "Das Haus Am Fluss", essay (3 versions), text in German, June 1960 (Box 40, Folder 603)
  - Karabuda, Barbro "The Silent Slaughter", essay, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 604)
  - Karabuda, Barbro and Günes "Terror in Guatemala", script, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 605)
  - The Orizuru-Kai "The Orizuru Kai History 1958-1960", pamphlet, [1960] (Box 40, Folder 606)
  - Pons, Maurice "Jamais plus Hiroshima", essay, text in French, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 607)
  - Puljizevic, Jozo "Ein Gespräch mit Edita Morris Tut Alles Was in Euerer Möglichkeit ist Gegen die Atombombe!", interview, text in German, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 608)
  - Reynolds, Barbara Leonard "Hiroshima, City of Hope", essay, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 609)
  - Rosten, Norman "Brooklyn Bridge", poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 610)
  - St. Paul's Cathedral "St. Matthew vii.16", sermon, 19 July 1964 (Box 40, Folder 611)
  - Schnall, Susan & Peter "Drug Abuse Among U.S. Troops in Vietnam and the Rise of Hepatitis Among the Population…A Political Problem", report, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 612)
  - Seaver, Elaine "End of Summer", poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 613)
  - Shima, Shosuke "To a Flowering Bouquet", poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 614)
  - Tamer, Ülkü "The Dewdrop", poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 615)
  - Tamer, Ülkü "Lady Zeynep", short story, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 616)
  - [Uenishi] "Noboho Article", short story (2 versions), n.d. (Box 40, Folder 617)
  - Woodward, Val "Ethical Consideration of the Question Defoliants or Mutagens?", essay, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 618)
  - Yoneda, Eisaku "Standing in the Rain", poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 619)
  - Unidentified Author "The Cemetery", poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 620)
  - Unidentified Author "The House Plant", poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 621)
  - Unidentified Author "Spring Blossoms", poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 622)
  - Unidentified Author Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 623)
- Series V: Subject Files
  - Subseries V.1: General
    Correspondence, reports, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, and other materials about topics of interest to the Morris’s. Arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - Africa, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 624)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 625)
    - Amnesty International, 1970-1971 (Box 40, Folder 626)
    - Asian Writers Congress, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 627)
    - Centre D'Etudes sur la Gauche Americaine (CEGA), n.d. (Box 40, Folder 628)
    - The Committee of Responsibility to Save War-Burned and War-Injured Vietnamese Children, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 629)
    - Cuba, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 630)
    - Di Pietro, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 631)
    - Disarmament, 1960-1971, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 632)
    - Environmental Protection, 1993, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 633)
    - Greece, 1957 & 1970 (Box 40, Folder 634)
    - Hiroshima, 1955-1965, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 635)
    - House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC), 1965, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 636)
    - India, 1950, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 637)
    - International Children's Centre, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 638)
    - Medical Ethics, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 639)
    - MENSA-France, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 640)
    - Military Establishment, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 641)
    - Nuclear War, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 642)
    - P.A.C.S. (Paris American Committee to Stopwar), 1966-1967, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 643)
    - P.E.N., 1948 & 1969, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 644)
    - Politics, 1958-1971, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 645)
    - Publications, 1964-1966, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 646)
    - Revolutionary Workers Party, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 647)
    - SANE (National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, Inc.), 1961, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 648)
    - Tupamaros, 1970-1971 (Box 41, Folder 649)
    - Turkey, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 650)
    - Vietnam, 1965-1971, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 651)
    - World Peace Study Mission, 1964, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 652)
  - Subseries V.2: Hiroshima House
    Correspondence, speeches, brochures, financial records, newspaper clippings, and related documents concerning the Hiroshima House. Founded by the Morris’s in May 1957, the house was a recreation center and hostel for the survivors of the atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Charitable Donations, 1965-1971 (Box 41, Folder 653)
    - Financial Statement, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 654)
    - Fundraising Letters, 1963-1967, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 655)
    - Hiroshima Health Bureau Reports Status of Livelihood of Atomic Bomb Survivors, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 656)
    - Inaugural Address for Opening of Hiroshima Rest House, [1957] (Box 42, Folder 657)
    - Journal #1 (Title calligraphy by Nobel Laureate Yasunari Kawabata), 1969 (Box 42, Folder 658)
    - Letter of Appreciation, Jan. 1965 (Box 42, Folder 659)
    - Message to be Read at 1000th Meeting, [1965] (Box 42, Folder 660)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 661)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1957-1966, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 662)
    - No One-No More, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 663)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 664)
    - Publicity, 1957-1967, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 665)
    - Radio Talk, [1957] (Box 42, Folder 666)
    - Receipts and Disbursements for 1963 and up to March 10, 1964, 1964 (Box 42, Folder 667)
    - Tanabe Talk, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 668)
    - Thank You Letter to Ira V. and Edita Morris from Atomic Bomb Survivors, 29 April 1967 (Box 42, Folder 669)
    - Yosegaki expressing condolences on Ira V. Morris's death from Atomic Bomb Survivors, n.d. (Box 14/16/5)
- Series VI: Notebooks
  Eight bound notebooks with handwritten notations, messages, drafts, and other information. The notes appear to have been written by Ira V. and Edita Morris. Arranged numerically by assigned number.
  - Notebook [#1], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 670)
  - Notebook [#2], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 671)
  - Notebook [#3], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 672)
  - Notebook [#4], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 673)
  - Notebook [#5], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 674)
  - Notebook [#6], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 675)
  - Notebook [#7], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 676)
  - Notebook [#8], n.d. (Box 43, Folder 677)
- Series VII: Address Books
  Five bound address books with handwritten entries. Arranged numerically by assigned number.
  - Address book [#1], n.d. (Box 43, Folder 678)
  - Address book [#2], n.d. (Box 43, Folder 679)
  - Address book [#3], n.d. (Box 43, Folder 680)
  - Address book [#4], n.d. (Box 43, Folder 681)
  - Address book [#5], n.d. (Box 43, Folder 682)
- Series VIII: Documents
  Legal documents, certificates, passports, lists, identification cards, and other records of Ira V. and Edita Morris. Included are wills for other Morris family members and materials related to Edwin Seaver and his wife, Elaine. Arranged chronologically.
  - Alien Registration Card for Edita D. E. Morris, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 683)
  - Excerpts from books and talks about Hiroshima, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 684)
  - List of Important Information for Edita re: our bank accounts, wills, etc., n.d. (Box 43, Folder 685)
  - List of Paris Contacts, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 686)
  - List of References for Edwin Seaver, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 687)
  - List of Works by Jess Gregg, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 688)
  - Lists of Books, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 689)
  - University Heidelberg Card for Ira V. Morris, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 690)
  - Passport for Ira V. Morris, 1922-1924 (Box 44, Folder 691)
  - Passport for Ira V. Morris, 1933 (Box 44, Folder 692)
  - Last Will and Testament for Ira N. Morris, 16 Dec. 1938 (Box 44, Folder 693)
  - Testamente of Maud Helga Elisabet Toll, text in Swedish, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 694)
  - Driver's License of Ira V. Morris, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 695)
  - Membership Cards for Edita Morris, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 696)
  - Passport for Edita Morris, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 697)
  - Authors Guild Membership Cards for Ira V. and Edita Morris, 1950 (Box 44, Folder 698)
  - French Identification Papers for Ira V. and Edita Morris, 1950 (Box 44, Folder 699)
  - Request for Cremation by Ira V. and Edita Morris, 4 May 1950 (Box 44, Folder 700)
  - Authors Guild Membership Cards for Ira V. Morris, 1951 (Box 44, Folder 701)
  - Certificat d'Immatriculation for Edita Morris, text in French, 1952-1953 (Box 44, Folder 702)
  - Driver's License of Ira V. Morris, 1953 (Box 44, Folder 703)
  - List of Books to get, Nov. 1955 (Box 44, Folder 704)
  - Visa from the Chinese Embassy, 1957 (Box 44, Folder 705)
  - Passport for Ira V. Morris, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 706)
  - Last Will and Testament for Edita Morris, 10 May 1965 (Box 44, Folder 707)
  - Last Will and Testament for Ira V. Morris, 10 May 1965 (Box 44, Folder 708)
  - Certificate of the Establishment of the Edita Morris Collection at Boston University, 1966 (Box 44, Folder 709)
  - Driver's License of Ira V. Morris, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 710)
  - Certificate proclaiming Edita Morris an Honorary Hiroshima Citizen, April 1967 (Box 681)
    [The certificate is in a red velveteen binding]
  - Last Will and Testament for Edita Morris, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 711)
  - Last Will and Testament for Ira V. Morris, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 712)
  - Certificate of Membership in Amnesty International for Ira V. Morris, 29 May 1968 (Box 44, Folder 713)
  - Last Will and Testament for Edita Morris, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 714)
  - List of Contributions, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 715)
  - Last Will and Testament for Ira V. Morris, 7 Jan. 1969 (Box 44, Folder 716)
  - Living Wills for Ira V. Morris, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 717)
  - Certification of Military Service for Edwin Seaver, 12 April 1971 (Box 44, Folder 718)